Today we're going to be talking about the three steps that you can take to
get your life back on track and how to get everything you want out of life.
We're here with Josh Terry today who's a coach
for top entrepreneurs and content creators all around the country.
So one of the most common things that people struggle with in their lives is
really finding purpose and figuring out exactly what they want to do to make them happy.
I want to ask you, maybe it's someone who's
coming out of college or 20 years into their career.
What is the first step that people need to take in order to really find something
fulfilling, really get their life back on track and find what brings them that purpose in life?
You have to figure out what you want. And I
don't mean that in like a big life sort of way.
I mean in the smallest possible thing. What do you want to
do today? What do you want to do in the next hour?
And then from there you can start to come up with a
set of things that you're willing to do based on that desire.
And then you can take action. And if you do it
in a small enough process, then you can start getting results.
What does that process look like for you?
It's three steps. You have to figure out what you want. You have
to figure out what you will do or give up to get it.
And then you have to come up with the smallest
reasonable next step that you can do in a cocky manner.
That is a process that can work in
10 minutes or it can work in a lifetime.
Oftentimes a lot of people struggle with falling into temptations, giving into those vices
that ultimately leads to maybe a depressive state and falling into a rut in life.
What do you emphasize with a lot of
your clients and the people that you work with?
To try and avoid giving into those vices
and kind of falling back into that rut.
There's a lot of people that want to be better.
And kind of the first step for a lot
of people in doing that is stopping doing bad things.
But people get stuck there where they think, oh, I
need to not do anything that I want to do.
I need to discipline myself. I need to behave.
I need to, you know, not do any bad stuff.
But if you live that way where you're trying to
never do anything that you find yourself like excited to do,
not doing anything that you find yourself
wanting to do, you start to lose enthusiasm.
For life, you start to shrink. You start to
lose sort of like a zest for life, a power.
But if you go after something that you're really
excited about, you get powerful, you turn into an animal.
So the way to hack that is learn
the difference between a desire and a craving,
because now you can actually
chase after stuff that you want.
Just chase after the things that make you better.
You are a coach
for entrepreneurs, professionals, content creators.
You're a content creator yourself.
You've built a massive following.
Joe Rogan actually follows you, which is pretty awesome.
And so what's kind of your process for idea generation,
whether it's for your business or for your career?
I think it's really important to
have a strong foundation for your business.
For content creators or anything that
people are wanting to do in life.
Take a walk. And what I mean
by that is create space for ideas.
A lot of us are
moving from one activity to another.
We actually can't sit in silence.
So it's like I'm working on
my job, I'm working on my project,
and now I'm taking a break from those things.
But, you know, I don't know what
activity I want to go to next.
So I'm going to scroll on my
phone until I get to that activity.
Oh, now I know what activity I'm going
to do. So now I'm going to do that.
There's actually no real silence
in there. There's no real break.
So you have to sit in silence.
You have to sit in silence for
a long enough for something to come up,
which is scary because that's where the demons are.
You're going to think things, right? You
got to hear what's in your own mind.
So the number one rule for ideas
is give yourself enough space for them.
So someone has that idea.
They found that theme that,
you know, brings in that excitement,
that gives them that burning desire and passion.
But what is the first step that someone should
really take to go all in with that theme?
Don't go all in. Learn how
to pull back a little bit.
Look at your life. Maintain it.
Live a good life and then take
10 minutes to commit fully to something.
Most of us want to go
all in as a way of escaping.
Most of us want to go all in as a
way of letting go of the real struggle of life.
That is, you have to maintain a lot of things.
The way to learn the skill of
all in is to do it in segments.
Is there a project that you
can commit to for a week?
And then can you do it again next week?
Where it's like, yes, this is
the thing that I care about.
This is the thing I'm going to win at.
But it's not going to take over
my entire identity or my entire life.
It's just, I'm going to learn how
to put all of my life into it.
And I'm going to put
my energy into it and win.
And from there, you develop the skill of all in.
And this is how you can become a stable
person who has the pillars of his life maintained.
But at the same time is
acting really powerfully in his passion.
So if I'm somebody that I know what
I want to do and I start executing,
but I get to a certain point where
things just aren't working, obstacles are coming up.
It's becoming really challenging.
Maybe I don't love the thing that I
thought I wanted as much as I do.
How do you kind of get there?
How do you get through that maybe reflection period or that
obstacle period of when you're actually trying to execute on something?
The number one thing that I do is I ignore the
problem completely with a lot of the people that I work with.
Because right now, one of
the biggest issues is overstimulation.
And it's not actually that somebody doesn't like the thing.
It's not actually that somebody's lost
their passion and is not getting results.
It's that they're staring at the phone for 16 hours.
It's that they're addicted to Netflix.
They're drinking too much.
They're enjoying the fruits of their labor in
some way that is making it impossible to labor.
It's almost like they're coming up with an
excuse and making a bigger problem out of like,
oh, I don't really love
the thing that I'm working on.
Like I have all these issues and
not really taking steps to overcome them,
even though I'm trying to execute on what I want.
And it's really it's just that they're
doing other things to fill that void.
Oftentimes, the fundamental part of people's success
is having a really good support system
and finding those people around them that are able to
support their desires and the things that they're trying to achieve.
What do you recommend to people to try and
find that outlet of people in that strong support system?
Start by believing that it's there.
Because a lot of people don't even think that it's
possible to have people around them that would support them
because they're surrounded by people that tear them down.
That's really common, sadly.
So first, believe that it's possible and then try to
get any exposure to the good stuff that you can,
you know, whether that's books, podcasts, content, whatever.
But then don't get addicted to that and then
start finding communities where people are doing good stuff.
If you guys are enjoying this video, make sure that you
leave a like and subscribe for tons of great content coming
and stay tuned because we're going
to get into it with Josh.
How once you find success, you can maintain it.
We talked about how to find what
you want and how to execute on that.
But I want to ask you, once you find that success, what
is the best thing that you can do in order to maintain that
and not get complacent in your life?
You have to figure out what makes you complacent.
For some people, that's being bored.
For some people, it's that they
were only working because they were panicking
and now they're working on something that they don't
really care about, but their life is taken care of.
So they don't need to panic anymore.
You know, it's things like that.
But the way you move out of complacency when you have success
is to move towards desire as opposed to run away from pain.
And so once you get success, you have to start asking
yourself, actually, what would be nice to have in the world?
What would be good?
And then let's move towards it.
And then let's chase after it.
Not in this like hedonistic, I'm hollowly chasing
after shallow things that don't get me satisfaction.
It's not that.
But it's where you're actually driving
towards the thing that you really like.
And when you do that, you develop a different type of motivation
that works even when you're in the comfort of your 75 bedroom mansion.
How can someone get over imposter syndrome?
And what is imposter syndrome for anybody that doesn't know?
So imposter syndrome is believing that you aren't the person that you think you should
be or that other people believe you are or that maybe you don't deserve to be.
If you are suddenly, you know, thrown into the forefront of public attention and
from some song that you wrote, you know, everybody says you're this amazing musician.
And you think, well, you
know, like I didn't produce it.
I just wrote this song.
Or you think, you know, like
I'm not that good of a musician.
There's many other musicians that are better than me.
It doesn't matter.
Your song was a hit song.
People were into it.
People liked you.
Now they like you.
That's the way it is.
And so you have to one, look at it from an evidence
based framework where you go, okay, I have this level of attention.
This is what's happening to me.
And that's the way it is.
And then two, you have to stop questioning about
whether or not you deserve it and start questioning it.
And that's the way it is.
And then you have to stop questioning
about whether or not you deserve it.
And start questioning it.
And start questioning what you're
going to do moving forward.
What are two to three self-improvement tips that you think everybody
should implement throughout their lives to set themselves up for success?
Learn breathwork, period.
Find the right diet that works for you.
For me, I started carnivore.
And then take the pathetic next best step.
Those are the three.
Breathwork has had an insane effect on my life.
You can learn to put yourself in ridiculous states.
You can learn to relax yourself, heal
yourself, sleep better, get smarter, have better ideas.
All of that stuff is possible.
Just keep going.
Just do breathwork.
And then diet.
My life never took off
until I got diet under control.
There was a time when I was a sugar
addict and I was very close to diabetes, I think.
Extremely sick.
Terrible situation.
And now I'm extremely healthy.
Like, you know, I can kick my 20-year-old self around.
I do a pretty good job with it.
For me, that was finding the carnivore diet.
I lived off of beef,
salt, and water for 14 months.
Now I eat meat and a
little bit of fruit here and there.
And it saved my life.
And for some people, that's probably terrible.
You've got to find the thing that works for you.
And then the last thing,
take the pathetic next best step.
Like, that's my favorite little saying
for how to make progress, right?
Is like, stop thinking about all the big things and can you take this tiny little
thing that you know you need to do and then do it with your chest out?
Like, do it cocky.
And be like, yeah, that thing that
I needed to do, I did it.
It's done and I'm proud.
Guys, that wraps up today's video.
Thank you so much for tuning in.
We're super pumped to be
able to film with Josh today.
Josh, where can everybody find you?
Across all social media at Josh Terry Plays.
And then if you're interested in working
with me, just shoot me a DM.
For more videos like these, click right here to go over the five
skill sets that everyone needs to become a better man in today's world.
If you enjoyed today's video, be sure to leave a
like and subscribe for tons of amazing content coming soon.